Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
So, Marco, what are we talking about here today?
那么，Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
Today we're going shopping again.
今天我们又要去购物了。
We go shopping a lot here at EnglishPod, but this is an upper intermediate level lesson,
我们在EnglishPod经常聊购物，但这是一节中高级课程，
so we've got some very specific terminology to cover.
所以我们要讲一些非常具体的术语。
Exactly.
没错。
We're going shopping for a digital camera, so we're going to be talking about very specific,
我们要去买一台数码相机，所以会讨论一些非常具体、
maybe a little bit technical vocab related to this very fascinating and expensive product.
可能有点技术性的词汇，跟这个既迷人又昂贵的产品有关。
All right.
好的。
I'm very excited.
我很兴奋。
I recently purchased a camera, but we won't talk about that yet.
我最近刚买了一台相机，但我们先不谈这个。
Let's take a listen to the dialogue for the first time, and when we come back, we can
我们先听一遍对话，等回来之后，
talk about some of the really interesting details.
再聊聊一些非常有趣的细节。
Hello, ma'am.
你好，女士。
Can I help you find something?
需要我帮你找点什么吗？
Yes, actually.
是的，确实。
I'm looking to buy a camera.
我想买一台相机。
We've got a wide selection.
我们有很多选择。
Do you know if you'd like a point and shoot or something a little fancier?
您想要傻瓜相机还是更高级一点的？
Are you shopping for yourself or for someone else?
您是给自己买还是给别人买？
Actually, I'm buying a camera for my husband.
实际上，我是给我丈夫买相机。
Ah, well, then I'd recommend a nice entry level digital SLR.
啊，那我推荐一款不错的入门级数码单反相机。
Yeah.
嗯。
Can I take a look at the SLRs you carry?
我能看看你们有哪些单反相机吗？
Sure thing.
当然可以。
Follow me.
跟我来。
This here is the...
这台是……
The Canon EOS.
佳能EOS。
Yeah, it's okay, but I'm looking for something that performs better in low light, has a better
嗯，还行，但我在找一款在弱光下表现更好、显示屏更好、
display panel, and longer battery life.
电池续航更长的相机。
Oh, uh, um, the Nikon D60 is a nice option.
哦，呃，嗯，尼康D60是个不错的选择。
Yeah, but what kit lens does this camera come with?
嗯，但这台相机配什么套机镜头？
I don't want some bulky telephoto lens.
我不想要那种笨重的长焦镜头。
Uh, well, this one has the, uh...
呃，嗯，这台配的是，呃……
Looks to me like an 18 to 55 millimeter lens.
看起来是18到55毫米的镜头。
Pretty standard.
很标准。
That'll do.
那还行。
Not like my husband will be stalking celebrities or anything.
反正我丈夫也不会去偷拍名人什么的。
Ah, so, um, can I interest you in any acc...
啊，那么，我能推荐您一些配……
Accessories?
配件吗？
Do you carry polarizing filters?
你们有偏振滤镜吗？
Polarizing filters?
偏振滤镜？
Um, we should.
嗯，我们应该有。
I'm sorry, ma'am, looks like we're sold out.
抱歉，女士，看起来我们卖完了。
No, you're not.
不，你们没有。
There are some right here.
这里就有一些。
Oh, well, would you look at that.
哦，嗯，你看这个。
Polarizing filters.
偏振滤镜。
Thanks for your help, Ralph.
谢谢你的帮助，Ralph。
No problem, ma'am.
不客气，女士。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So apparently this girl knew more than the salesman about this, uh, these things.
看来这位女士比售货员更懂这些东西。
Is this from real life experience?
这是来自真实生活经历吗？
Maybe.
也许吧。
Uh, well, we can get to that later, like I said, but, uh, there are some very important
嗯，我们稍后再聊这个，但，呃，有一些非常重要的词，
words that anyone who wants to buy a camera should know before they go into the store,
任何想买相机的人在进店前都应该知道，
and these are common across the board.
而且这些词是通用的。
So let's take a look at these in today's Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看今天“语言要点”里的内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright, so in Language Takeaway today we have our first, um, difference.
好的，在今天的“语言要点”里，我们首先有一个区别。
Now it's very important to know the difference between point and shoot camera and the digital
现在，了解傻瓜相机和数码单反相机之间的区别非常重要。
SLR.
数码单反相机。
Okay, so digital, everyone knows digital now, right?
好的，数码，现在大家都知道数码，对吧？
That's the kind of photography we have.
这就是我们现在用的摄影方式。
You don't use film, okay?
你不用胶卷，对吧？
Use the memory card.
用存储卡。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Um, to record digital images, but point and shoot are those little cameras where you just
嗯，来记录数码图像，但傻瓜相机就是那种小相机，
click and it takes a picture.
你只要按一下就能拍照。
There's no lens, a special, there's no additional lens, there's no special add-ons.
没有镜头，没有特殊的附加镜头，没有特殊的配件。
It's a small rectangle and you just take normal pictures.
就是一个小方块，你拍普通的照片。
And that's the kind of camera that like my mom uses.
就像我妈妈用的那种相机。
Everyone usually has those.
大家通常都有那种。
I have it in my purse and whatever.
我把它放在包里什么的。
It's just easy to use.
就是很容易用。
Um, but the digital SLR is the kind of camera that's like the old SLR where you have an,
嗯，但数码单反相机就像老式单反相机一样，
like an attachment of a, you have a body and you have a lens and they're just much fancier
你有一个可拆卸的，你有一个机身和一个镜头，它们要高级得多，
and you have to do a lot more on your own to make a nice picture.
而且你得自己做更多事情才能拍出好照片。
Now SLR, that's an acronym.
现在SLR是个缩写。
Do you know what it stands for?
你知道它代表什么吗？
So an SLR is a single lens reflex camera and that means that there's a lot more you have
SLR是单镜头反光相机，这意味着作为摄影师，
to do as the photographer to make sure that the picture comes out well.
你要做更多事情来确保照片拍得好。
Right, so it's really interesting because you can actually play with the lens, like
对，这真的很有趣，因为你可以实际调节镜头，
the focus and you know how much light you want to allow it to go in.
比如对焦，你知道你想让多少光线进入。
And there's a lot of really, you know, sometimes a little bit difficult things that not many
而且有很多真的，你知道，有时候有点难懂的东西，
people understand.
不是很多人能理解。
Exactly.
没错。
And so I think that's why it's good to do some research before you buy one because there's
所以我认为在买之前做些研究是好的，
so many differences across the different cameras.
因为不同相机之间有很多差异。
Okay, now both on digital SLRs and on point and shoot cameras, you have something that's
好的，现在在数码单反和傻瓜相机上，
called the display panel.
你都有个叫显示屏的东西。
That's right.
没错。
The display panel is usually covered in plastic and it's the area that tells you how many
显示屏通常用塑料覆盖，是显示你拍了多少张照片、
pictures you've taken, how many pictures you can take, if the flash is on, if you're doing
还能拍多少张、闪光灯是否开启、是否在自动模式的地方。
an automatic setting.
所以它就像个小电脑显示器，告诉你相机的情况。
So it's like the little computer monitor that tells you what's going on with the camera.
通常拍完照片后，你也能看到拍得怎么样，对吧？
Usually after you take a picture, you can also see how it came out, right?
在那一刻。
In that moment.
没错。
Exactly.
所以很多时候，对于这些高级相机，
And so a lot of times with these fancy cameras, you want to know how big the display panel
你想知道显示屏有多大，质量有多好。
is and how good the quality is in the display panel.
因为显然，如果你拍了照片，在显示屏上显示得不好，
Because obviously if you take a picture and it shows up bad in the display panel, you
你想重拍一张。
want to take a new one.
但如果是显示屏坏了呢？
But what if it's the display panel that's broken?
对，对。
Right, right.
好的，非常好。
Okay, very good.
这实际上是数码相机的一大优势，
And that's actually one of the great advantages of digital cameras that you can actually see
你可以实际看到照片的样子。
how your picture looks like.
没错。
Exactly.
在那一刻。
In that moment.
即时满足。
Instant gratification.
不错。
Nice.
好的。
All right.
现在，当她打算买这台数码单反时，
Now when she was looking to buy this digital SLR, she mentioned something about a kit lens.
她提到了套机镜头。
Okay, this is fancy camera terminology, right?
好的，这是高级相机的术语，对吧？
Because if you buy a point and shoot, there's no lens.
因为如果你买傻瓜相机，没有镜头。
It's just the camera.
就是相机本身。
But if you're buying a fancy digital SLR, you can buy the body, which means the machine,
但如果你要买一台高级的单反相机，你可以只买机身，也就是相机本身，
but there's no lens.
但没有镜头。
So normally people will sell, stores will sell cameras with a kit lens.
所以通常商店卖相机时会配一个套机镜头。
That means they make a kit or they make a combination for you.
也就是说他们会为你准备一个套装或组合。
So it's the body and the lens.
就是机身和镜头一起。
Exactly.
没错。
But if you want, you can buy the body and the lens separate.
但如果你愿意，也可以分开买机身和镜头。
Maybe you want a really fancy lens.
也许你想要一个特别高级的镜头。
Exactly.
没错。
So what's the kind of fancy lens we might buy?
那我们可能会买哪种高级镜头呢？
A telephoto lens.
长焦镜头。
Ooh.
哦。
So these are the really big lenses for super close up shots from a distance, right?
就是那种特别大的镜头，用来从远处拍超近的特写，对吧？
So you think of maybe professional photographers or photojournalists who had these kinds of
你会想到那些专业摄影师或摄影记者，他们用这种
lenses.
镜头。
They're big and they're bulky and they're not for traveling.
它们又大又笨重，不适合旅行携带。
Usually you see them in like sporting events, right?
通常你在体育赛事中能看到它们，对吧？
They're on the side of the field and they have these big white, they're usually white
他们站在场地边上，相机上装着那种白色的大
lenses on their cameras.
镜头。
So you can actually take a very close picture of the action that's far away.
这样你就能拍到远处动作的近距离照片。
Exactly.
没错。
And it's really good for those kinds of things where you have action or where you're trying
这种镜头非常适合拍摄动作场景或想拍
to get close ups.
特写的时候。
And now if one of these accessories that could go well with a telephoto lens or any digital
现在，有一种配件可以和长焦镜头或任何数码
SLR is a polarizing filter.
单反相机搭配得很好，那就是偏振滤镜。
Okay, so filter is something that takes certain elements out of something else.
好的，滤镜就是能从某物中去除某些元素的东西。
So we can filter coffee for example and it takes the coffee grounds out and leaves the
比如我们可以过滤咖啡，把咖啡渣滤掉，留下
water.
水。
But in a camera, a polarizing filter is something we put onto the glass of the lens to change
但在相机上，偏振滤镜是我们放在镜头玻璃上的东西，用来改变
the way that light goes into the lens.
光线进入镜头的方式。
Okay.
好的。
So in this way you take a picture maybe of a very sunny day and it will look differently
这样，你在阳光明媚的日子拍照时，效果会和
if you didn't have this filter.
没有这个滤镜时不一样。
Exactly.
没错。
And you can also have a UV filter which does similar things with UV rays in the sunlight.
你还可以用UV滤镜，它对阳光中的紫外线有类似的作用。
And these are just filters or things you put on the camera and polarizing means that you're
这些就是装在相机上的滤镜或东西，而偏振的意思是
splitting up the kind of light that goes in.
把进入的光线分开。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Very technical terms but they're very useful especially if you're looking to buy one of
这些术语很专业，但非常有用，特别是如果你想买一台
these cameras and you're not very familiar with the terms.
这样的相机，却对这些术语不太熟悉。
But why don't we move on now to some very interesting phrases that we saw in the dialogue
不过，我们不如现在转到Fluency Builder中对话里看到的一些
on Fluency Builder.
非常有趣的短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
All right.
好的。
So on Fluency Builder our first phrase today is entry level.
在Fluency Builder中，我们今天的第一个短语是“入门级”。
What's an entry level digital SLR?
什么是入门级数码单反相机？
Okay.
好的。
Well entry level is something that we can use for any kind of purchase.
嗯，“入门级”这个词可以用在任何类型的购买上。
So any kind of thing that we buy.
也就是我们买的任何东西。
In the case of a camera, an entry level is not for an expert or professional.
就相机而言，入门级不是给专家或专业人士用的。
It's something for someone who's buying one for the first time.
它是给第一次购买的人用的。
Like for beginners.
就像给初学者。
For beginners.
给初学者。
So entry level is like entry, beginning, starting.
所以“入门级”就像入门、开始、起步。
We can have an entry level job where you don't need training or experience.
我们可以有入门级的工作，不需要培训或经验。
An entry level camera where you don't need long experience with fancy cameras.
入门级相机，不需要长期使用高级相机的经验。
Or training to know how to use it.
或者培训才知道怎么用。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So that's an entry level camera but as you mentioned we can also use it for the job.
所以那是入门级相机，但正如你提到的，我们也可以用它来形容工作。
An entry level job position.
一个入门级的工作职位。
All right.
好的。
What about our second phrase?
那我们的第二个短语呢？
Okay.
好的。
So this one goes with the telephoto lens, right?
这个和长焦镜头有关，对吧？
She says I don't need a telephoto lens.
她说我不需要长焦镜头。
My husband doesn't need a telephoto lens.
我丈夫不需要长焦镜头。
It's not like he's going to be stalking celebrities.
他又不是要去跟踪名人。
Okay.
好的。
So we have this verb here.
所以我们这里有一个动词。
To stalk.
跟踪。
That means to follow someone around.
意思是到处跟着某人。
Okay.
好的。
And to look at them and to watch them and to not leave them alone.
看着他们，盯着他们，不让他们独处。
Now she mentioned this because this is a very interesting and closely associated topic with
她提到这个是因为这是一个非常有趣且与摄影师紧密相关的
photographers.
话题。
You know you have the paparazzi who follow celebrities and they have these big telephoto
你知道有狗仔队跟踪名人，他们用那种大长焦
lens so they can take pictures of celebrities without them knowing.
镜头，这样就能在名人不知情的情况下拍照。
Exactly.
没错。
And so you imagine someone in a tree with a big telephoto lens taking a photo of someone
所以你可以想象有人躲在树上，用大长焦镜头拍某个
famous who's you know half a mile away.
半英里外的名人。
And stalking celebrities is something that's a bad thing, right?
跟踪名人是一件坏事，对吧？
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
It's bad.
这是不好的。
But it's very common.
但很常见。
And also illegal I think.
而且我觉得也是违法的。
And I think it's illegal.
我认为是违法的。
All right.
好的。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们的最后一个短语呢？
Would you look at that?
你看看这个？
Well he said it in a very surprised tone, right?
嗯，他用很惊讶的语气说的，对吧？
Kind of like he didn't really expect to find the polarizing filters.
好像他真没想到会找到偏振滤镜。
Right.
对。
So he's embarrassed.
所以他很尴尬。
Okay.
好的。
Would you look at that means oh wow I'm surprised.
“你看看这个”意思是哦哇，我很惊讶。
Right.
对。
Uh huh.
嗯哼。
Right.
对。
So it's awkward.
所以这很尴尬。
Right.
对。
So you could say Marco you got a little bit of food on your shirt?
所以你可以说马可，你衬衫上有点食物？
You've had it for like an hour.
你沾上都快一个小时了。
Oh my God.
哦天哪。
Would you look at that?
你看看这个？
Oh the beans I had.
哦，我吃的豆子。
That's really embarrassing.
真尴尬。
I've got food on my shirt.
我衬衫上沾了食物。
So this man who works at the store, he's embarrassed because he didn't know something he should
所以这个在店里工作的男人，他因为不知道本该知道的事情而
know.
尴尬。
Okay.
好的。
And so he says oh would you look at that?
于是他说哦，你看看这个？
How funny.
真有趣。
I didn't see those.
我没看到那些。
Now we can also maybe use it in a sarcastic tone, right?
我们也可以用讽刺的语气说，对吧？
If I tell somebody can you bring me my glasses that are on the table?
如果我告诉别人，你能把桌上我的眼镜拿给我吗？
And they're like I can't find them.
然后他们说找不到。
They're not here.
它们不在这儿。
And then I find them.
然后我找到了它们。
Would you look at that?
你看看这个？
Here they are.
它们在这儿。
Right?
对吧？
On your head the whole time.
一直在你头上。
That's my mom.
那是我妈妈。
Would you look at that?
你看看这个？
I've been wearing my glasses the whole time.
我一直戴着我的眼镜。
Alright.
好了。
Very good.
非常好。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be back to talk about
那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来聊聊
digital SLRs.
数码单反相机。
Hello ma'am.
您好，女士。
Can I help you find something?
需要我帮您找点什么吗？
Yes actually.
是的，确实。
I'm looking to buy a camera.
我想买一台相机。
We've got a wide selection.
我们有很多选择。
Do you know if you'd like a point and shoot or something a little fancier?
您想要傻瓜相机还是更高级一点的？
Are you shopping for yourself or for someone else?
您是给自己买还是给别人买？
Actually I'm buying a camera for my husband.
实际上，我是给我丈夫买相机。
Ah well then I'd recommend a nice entry level digital SLR.
啊，那我推荐一款不错的入门级数码单反相机。
Yeah?
是吗？
Can I take a look at the SLRs you carry?
我能看看你们卖的数码单反吗？
Sure thing.
当然可以。
Follow me.
跟我来。
This here is the...
这是……
The Canon EOS.
佳能EOS。
Yeah it's okay but I'm looking for something that performs better in low light, has a better
嗯，还行，但我在找一款在弱光下表现更好、有更好的
display panel and longer battery life.
显示屏和更长电池寿命的。
Oh ah um the Nikon D60 is a nice option.
哦，嗯，尼康D60是个不错的选择。
Yeah but what kit lens does this camera come with?
是啊，但这台相机配什么套机镜头？
I don't want some bulky telephoto lens.
我不想要那种笨重的长焦镜头。
Ah well this one has the um...
啊，这个配的是……
Looks to me like an 18-55mm lens.
看起来是18-55mm的镜头。
Pretty standard.
很标准。
That'll do.
那还行。
Not like my husband will be stalking celebrities or anything.
反正我丈夫也不会去偷拍名人什么的。
Ah ha ha.
啊哈哈。
So um can I interest you in any acce...
那，我能向您推荐一些配……
Accessories?
配件吗？
Do you carry polarizing filters?
你们有偏光滤镜吗？
Polarizing filters.
偏光滤镜。
Um we should.
嗯，我们应该有。
I'm sorry ma'am looks like we're sold out.
抱歉，女士，看起来我们卖完了。
No you're not.
不，你们没有。
There's some right here.
这儿就有一些。
Oh well would you look at that.
哦，你看看这个。
Polarizing filters.
偏光滤镜。
Thanks for your help...
谢谢你的帮助……
Ralph.
拉尔夫。
No problem ma'am.
不客气，女士。
Alright we're back so you mentioned you recently bought a digital SLR camera.
好了，我们回来了，你提到你最近买了一台数码单反相机。
How's that working out?
用得怎么样？
I'm loving it.
我非常喜欢。
I'm...
我……
I have to actually train myself on how to use it because I used to have an old film
我得自己学着怎么用，因为我以前有一台老式的胶片
camera that had...
相机，它……
It was actually a Nikon as well and it's uh...
其实也是尼康的，嗯……
It's different using a digital SLR.
用数码单反感觉不一样。
There's a lot of things you can do that are very fancy because you...
有很多很高级的功能，因为……
You actually...
实际上……
There's a computer inside essentially.
里面基本上有一台电脑。
So it's uh...
所以嗯……
It's...
它……
I'm getting used to it.
我正在慢慢适应。
It's fine.
还行。
So what's the difference in pictures like from a point and shoot to a digital SLR?
那傻瓜相机和数码单反拍出来的照片有什么区别？
Does it really make a great difference?
真的有很大区别吗？
Are you very happy with it?
你对它很满意吗？
There is a big difference and part of the difference is that you can control every aspect
区别很大，部分原因在于你可以控制照片的每一个
of the photo.
方面。
So my digital camera was a small little Canon.
我的数码相机是一台小小的佳能。
You know the little...
你知道那种小……
What are they called?
叫什么来着？
The Power Shoot?
Power Shoot？
And it made...
它拍……
It took great pictures because you know these cameras have amazing pixel quality.
它拍出来的照片很棒，因为你知道这些相机有惊人的像素质量。
They have like 7.1 megapixels or like 9.1 megapixels.
它们有大概710万像素或者910万像素。
So the quality is really good.
所以质量真的很好。
But everything looks the same.
但所有照片看起来都一样。
If I have my digital camera, my digital SLR, I can frame a shot and I can focus on one
如果我用我的数码单反，我可以构图，对焦在一个人身上，
person but make everyone else blurry.
让其他人都模糊。
I can really make more artistic photos whereas the point and shoot is great for parties and
我真的能拍出更有艺术感的照片，而傻瓜相机更适合派对和
for everyday stuff.
日常使用。
Just like everyday stuff.
就是日常的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Now what about traveling?
那旅行的时候呢？
You have a dilemma there, right?
你有个两难的选择，对吧？
Because you visit very beautiful places where you would love to take very nice pictures
因为你去了很美的地方，很想用数码单反拍出很棒的照片，
with a digital SLR but at the same time the inconvenience of it of actually...
但同时它又不方便，因为……
Because they're pretty big.
它们挺大的。
All of them are pretty big.
所有数码单反都挺大的。
So where would you go on that?
那你会怎么选？
Would you use the point and shoot or the digital SLR?
你会用傻瓜相机还是数码单反？
Well that's a good question.
嗯，这是个好问题。
One of the reasons that I picked the lens that I did is because it's not immense but
我选这个镜头的原因之一就是它不算巨大，但
I really want to be able to do some like landscape photography and I travel a lot so I think
我真的很想能拍一些风景照，而且我经常旅行，所以我觉得
it's worthwhile to suck it up and just take the camera because otherwise why did you buy
忍一忍带上相机是值得的，不然你买它干嘛，
it, right?
对吧？
Yeah, that's true.
是啊，没错。
Alright, so an interesting topic here on EnglishPod and I'm sure a lot of our users travel around,
好了，今天EnglishPod的话题很有趣，我相信很多用户经常旅行，
like to take pictures or maybe are experts on digital photography so why don't you come
喜欢拍照，或者可能是数码摄影专家，所以欢迎你们来
to the website EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you there and until next time.
我们那儿见，下次再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
For EnglishPod, I'm Dziękuję and have a great weekend.
这里是EnglishPod，我是Dziękuję，祝大家周末愉快。